CURRICULUM VITAE

PHYLLIS OBOTE-LUKORITO

Address: P.O. Box 23375-00625, Nairobi Kenya, Mobile: +254 722 672 165 E-mail: phyllis.lukorito@gmail.com, Nationality: Kenyan

SUMMARY

Experienced public health and certified sustainable business executive; driven by integrity and strong ethical principles. A confident leader with a passion for smart business improvement with experience in advocacy, stakeholder engagement and compliance. Effectively communicates and reframes complex issues. Strong team player and leader; inspires and challenges others to achieve their potential.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Public health
- PPP management
- Sustainability- ESG
- Stakeholder Engagement
- Board and Team Leadership
- Compliance

- Strategic Planning and Integration
- Business Ethics
- Advocacy
- Social Behaviour change Implementation

CAPABILITIES

- Over ten years of results-based business management coupled with knowledge of regulatory and nutrition environment across Africa as a driver and catalyst for sustainable business.
- In depth understanding of innovation and renovation as a growth driver within the business by identifying gaps/opportunities in the Food systems.
- Stakeholder engagement and advocacy leveraging the scientific knowledge across the network to build sustainable partnerships.
- Evaluation of PPPs using Sustainable Transparent Effective Partnerships (STEP) methodology
- Good communication skills and stake holder management on public affairs.
- Experienced in managing budgets and P&L

CAREER ACHIEVENMENTS

2021: Successfully advocated for blend flex labelling with the regulatory bodies (a practice relatively new in Africa) to accommodate the fluctuating oil prices which would have otherwise been costly to the business changing pack materials and write offs of unused materials.

2018: Successfully led the transition from Unilever on regulatory and compliance across the Africa markets Upfield operates in ensuring the registration needs of various countries were met, risks were minimized, and country product-submission processes were streamlined during the divestment of the spreads business from Unilever.

2017: Successful launch of the sustainable nutrition campaign on good breakfast that involved local sourcing of rapeseed oil a key ingredient in manufacture of margarine and innovation of the product as part of the sustainable nutrition way of doing business. As part of the behaviour change worked with GAIN to educate local communities on good farming practices, nutrition & hygiene practices; under the "seeds of prosperity" program that gained global recognition.

2015: Spearheaded the Nestle Nutrition Institute Africa to be recognized as a partner for Health Care Professional leading to the launch of the ESPGHAN course in East Africa which benefitted over 100 Health Care Professionals.

2014: Initiated the Nutritional Landscaping in collaboration with the DRC government to identify nutritional deficiencies in DRC and give insight to the business for Innovation & Renovation projects which resulted into successful launch of iron fortified products

2011: Launched basic nutrition training course for all employees across the region achieving 90% coverage as part of Nestle's commitment to driving Nutrition Health & Wellness among employees

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

June 2018 to Present : Upfield Foods Limited

Head of Regulatory Affairs and Nutrition Africa

Part of the transition team in the divestment of the spreads business out of Unilever. Working as part of the team to ensure the new organization is set up for operations across Africa. Deliver enhanced consumer protection and global advocacy to ensure the business maintains license to operate in all markets. Develop and implement the global regulatory harmonization initiatives on ingredients to support product innovation and growth

- Generated regulatory documents including Technical Files, Declarations of Conformity, Certificates to Foreign Government, and Certificates of Origin used for product registration across the different countries in Africa.
- Drive advocacy priorities by developing strategic influencing plans and collaborate with key internal stakeholders to align plans in support of product innovation
- Lead in giving expert regulatory and nutrition guidance and recommendation in innovation & renovation of product portfolio across Africa.
- Lead overall compliance and initiate process improvement to ensure compliance in all aspect of relevant regulatory/government regulations
- Partner with category leaders in managing new and emerging regulations, access their impact to the business and execute plans to ensure continuous business operation.
- Ensure the products are aligned to the CODEX guidelines and local regulations as applicable.
- Lead and review Nutrition & Health advocacy strategy for Blue Band with focus on the social mission program across Africa engaging key KOFs and health sector stakeholders.
- Build relationships and be involved with external regulators, key trade associations and working groups, as well as key opinion formers. Represent the company in external meeting with the stakeholders.

March 2016 to May 2018: Unilever

Nutrition & Health Manager Africa

Working with corporate leadership and teams to develop, implement, and communicate corporate Sustainable Nutrition efforts in the foods business. Work ranges from integrated strategic planning to project management, product innovation & renovation, strategic communication, and training: employee and stakeholder engagement, supply chain, waste management, energy, and facilities.

Key Responsibilities:

- Shape and lead the regional Nutrition & Health Agenda for Foods Africa in strategic partnership with the Africa Category and Cluster leadership team.
- Work with business to unlock the role that responsible business can play in creating positive social impact by creating sustainable PPP that deliver impact and scale across the value chain.
- Lead and review Nutrition & Health advocacy strategy for key brands that ensures that key health sector stakeholders are involved.
- Design, execute and evaluate behaviour change programs that are scientifically based.
- Adapt and deploy centrally developed Nutrition communication approach and materials for both local "health influencers" (experts, health care professionals, NGOs, GOs, media, social networks and customers) and

- local consumers aimed at influencing local consumer behaviour to create demand for Unilever products in an effective way.
- Business partnering and stakeholder management which includes stakeholders such as Country Managers, Brand Development and Brand Building Directors and senior external stakeholders

May 2015 to February 2016: Nestlé Equatorial African Region

Medical & Scientific Affairs Manager

Strategic partnership with Key Opinion Leaders in a highly regularized and legislated area of Infant Nutrition. My main responsibilities involved creating a platform for the business to showcase products, scientific knowledge to health care professionals and provide leadership to the Nestle Nutrition Institute Africa.

Key Responsibilities:

- Develop strategy to engage medical fraternity in Science and Nutrition and popularizing scientific activities within health care fraternity.
- Provide timely scientific inputs and value-added responses to medical and nutrition queries from medical professionals, patient groups, government authorities and field force to strengthen relationship with these stakeholders
- Maintain and develop relationship with the Key Contacts from medical community to ensure a positive share
 of Voice for Nestle. Develop a set of Key Contacts as 'Speakers'/Script writers for Round Table conferences
 / Articles
- Continuously update medical/ product knowledge of field force and marketing group in coordination with the training team by devising and utilizing innovative methods of medical training.
- Build the image of the NNI in Africa as the Healthcare Professional's partner in advancing understanding of the science of nutrition

October 2010 to April 2015: Nestlé Equatorial African Region

Regional NHW & Consumer Services Manager

At Nestle as the World's Largest Nutrition Health & Wellness Company my primary goal was to translate nutrition concepts both internally and externally. This involved strategic planning, documentation, activation of the NHW manifesto within the brands, to the consumers, employees and external stakeholders.

Key responsibilities:

- Drive mindset change around Nutrition Health & Wellness in the region for the business units to embed NHW in the plans and Strategies ensuring this is embedded in the local Brand Essence
- Disseminate, influence and help implementation locally of the Company and SBU / GMB NHW Strategies
- Ensure the consumers have an active platform to reach Nestlé for assistance within EAR region; this is through consumer care lines, social media platforms and face to face consumer visits
- Organize internal activation to keep NHW top of mind
- Drive and own Market NHW Dashboard which supports external commitment to stakeholders on public health sensitive nutrients.

Jan 2010 to August 2010: Gertrude's Garden Children's Hospital

Head Hospital Nutritionist

July 2007 to August 2008: CARE International in Kenya (Emergency & Refugee Operations Dadaab Refugee Camp)

Infant & Young Child Feeding Nutritionist

Mar 2006- June 2007: Mulago National and referral Hospital (Kampala -Uganda)

Chief Nutritionist (Burns' and Plastic Surgery Unit)

July 2005– Feb 2006: Center for Nutrition Education & Research (CENER)

Nutritionist (Weight loss & Wellness)

EDUCATION

2008- 2009: United States International University-Africa, Nairobi.

Executive Master of Science in Organizational Development

Part of the Transformational Leadership Programme

2002 -2005: Kenyatta University

Bachelor of Science (Foods, Nutrition and Dietetics),

Baseline surveys: School age going children at risk of obesity in Nairobi

Skills Training

2021: University of Capetown

Public Relations

2020: London Business School

Sustainability Leadership and Corporate Responsibility

2019: The Graduate Institute, Geneva

Together for Nutrition- PPP Engagements

2010: Pediatric Endocrinology Training Center Africa

Certificate in Growth in Practice

2007: International Union of Health Promotion & Education

Certificate in Cardiovascular health promotion and chronic disease

Epidemiology and management

2005: Stellenbosch University

Certificate in weight loss management and treatment

Assessing risk factors, prevention and the strategies employed

INTERESTS & HOBBIES

Board games (Scrabble, Chess), Cooking, Hiking, Camping, Gyming, Swimming & Reading, Public health journals and self-improvement books

Referees

Ms. Jaki Wasike-Sihanya Founder Director, LifeSkills Coaching Consultants P.o Box 1313-00606

Mobile: +254 722 759 791

E-Mail: jaki@lifeskillscoaching.co.ke

Ms. Agnes Kitololo Category Director Africa, Pepsico South Africa, 1 Simba Rd, Parkhaven,Boksburg 1459, South Africa Mobile: +254 790 201 471

E-Mail: Agnes.Kitololo@pepsico.com

Ms. Alice A. Ojwang'
Nutrition and Dietetics Consultant
North West University-Centre of Excellence for Nutrition
11, Hoffman Street,
Building G16- Room 156
Potchefstroom, North West Province.
Republic of South Africa

Mobile: +27 60 929 4510 Email: ojwangaa@gmail.com